Shahin Nazarov

Around 5 years of software engineering experience working with **financial**, **banking**, **betting**, **cryptographic**, and **e-commerce** services companies involving extensive interaction and engagement with software design, documenting, testing, development as a **Senior Software Engineer**. Currently seeking **Software Engineering**, **Software Development**, and **Solution Architect** positions and would be keen to learn and get comfortable with new tools and technologies if the position requires it.



EXPERIENCES

International Bank of Azerbaijan OJSC, Azerbaijan — *Lead Software Engineer*

JAN 2021 - PRESENT

- Designing and developing a new Loyalty Program
- EDD implementation
- Planning and documenting technical specifications for features and system design
- Working closely with senior stakeholders to understand business requirements and help translate these to technical requirements for development team
- Writing testable, scalable and efficient codes and leading code reviews
- Directing development team in design, development, coding, testing and debugging of applications
- Mentoring junior team members and ensuring they adhere to determine software quality standards

Caspian Tech CJSC, Azerbaijan — Senior Software Engineer

MAY 2019 - JAN 2021

- Designing a new scalable **betting system**
- Making the standards for configurations, coding style, testing and documentation
- Applying zero-downtime deployment with Kubernetes technologies
- Making CD/CI infrastructure with versioning for all applications
- Creating and developing new applications both microservice and SOA based
- Implementing 3rd party odd providers (e.g. sportradar)
- Optimizing the betting system for passing provider's certification requirements
- Developing risk management system with real-time data analyzing

PaySis LLC, Azerbaijan — Senior Software Engineer

JUNE 2018 - MAY 2019

• Making the **payment system** support multiple payment

PERSONAL INFORMATION.

Address: 5 Cavadkhan street, Nasimi region, Baku, Azerbaijan

Nationality: Azerbaijani Birthday: 1997/04/01 Phone: +994708900999

Email:

me@shahinnazarov.com

Skype: shaheen.nazarov **LinkedIn**:<u>shaheen-nazarov</u>

Website:

shahinnazarov.com
GitHub: nazarov-pro

Twitter: <a>@shaheennnazarov

CERTIFICATIONS

CKAD: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (Expires: 02/2023).

OCP: Java SE 11 Developer

LANGUAGES

Azerbaijani (Native)

English (Professional)

- processors(e-comm)
- Implementing new integrations with aggregators and vendors
- Integrating with new payment processing systems (e.g. MasterPass)
- Optimizing the speed of the system using caching technologies
- Automating daily tasks for reporting
- Developing new projects and REST APIs for (mobile) clients

B.EST Solution LLC, Azerbaijan — Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2018

- Extending the open-source X-Road project by implementing new features
- Automating SOAP-based web services (generating STUB files and auto detecting new web services)
- Integrating e-signing services with Europe (OASIS DSS)
- Developing a management portal for signing/verifying
- Implementing CD/CI infrastructure and containerization all applications
- Optimizing the current system with implementing EDD patterns

CCI Technologies LLC, Azerbaijan — Software Developer

MAY 2016 - NOVEMBER 2017

- Developing new features for the ERP system
- Writing documentation for REST and SOAP web services
- Making UML diagrams(class, flow, use case, sequence)
- Applying new REST APIs in the client-side(web)
- Analysing & optimizing SQL scripts
- Resolving bugs in website and backend with the feedback of the client

EDUCATION

Azerbaijan State University of Oil and Industry, Azerbaijan — *Master*

Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) Engineering

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2019

Azerbaijan State University of Oil and Industry, Azerbaijan — *Bachelor*

Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) Engineering

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2017

Programming languages: Java (expert), Golang (proficient), C# (prior

experience), JavaScript (prior experience)

Software architectural design: Monolithic, Microservices, SOA, EDD, TDD, CQRS

SQL/ORM Frameworks: JPA, Hibernate, MyBatis, JOOQ

Spring Technologies: Spring Core, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring MVC, Spring

Data, Spring Security

Web Services: REST, SOAP, Grpc

Databases (RDBMS/NoSQL): OracleDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Version Control Systems: Git

DevOps Tools: Jenkins, TeamCity, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux Shell Scripting,

Nexus, ELK Stack, Graylog, Prometheus(with Grafana)

Other: Apache Kafka (Kafka Connect), RabbitMQ (with AMQP and MQTT

protocols), Maven, Gradle, Redis, Memcached, Cryptography